don't say rule it all out
不要說全部把它排除
don't do anything
千萬不要做任何事情
don't go too far
不要做太極端
we're talking about a trend
我們講的是一個趨勢
What kind of food is the person who chooses
到底是選用什麼樣的食物的人
He's not weak
他比較不是衰弱的
Of course, first of all, look at the international
當然首先也看看國際上
what kind of information
有什麼樣的一個資料
because he is so famous
因為他太有名了
so almost what disease
所以幾乎什麼病
Take it with mediterranean diet
大家都拿來和地中海飲食
let's discuss
來探討一下
when you were middle-aged
你中年的時候
overeating or when old
多吃或老年的時候
long-term intake
長期的攝取
If it is the form of the Mediterranean diet
如果是地中海飲食這個形態
Less prone to frailty
比較不容易得到衰弱症
Conversely, if it is a Western diet
反之如果是西方飲食形態
Just a lot of red meat burgers vegetarian
就是很多的紅肉 漢堡 素食
It is easier to suffer from debilitation
這樣就會比較容易有衰弱症
This is a study of Westerners
這是西方人的研究
But after all, there is no way we can combine the Mediterranean diet
但是畢竟我們沒有辦法把地中海飲食
apply to Taiwan
就套用到台灣
learn a little
學一點
but there is no way to completely
但是沒有辦法完全的
it looks like this
是這樣的一個樣子
people eat
人吃東西
It's not about how much you eat
並不是說這個東西你吃多少
Rather it is the emergence of a form
而是它是一個形態的出現
Suppose I eat a lot of red meat
假設我吃很多紅肉的話
I have no room in my stomach for tofu
我肚子就沒有空間吃豆腐
or fish and shrimp
或者是魚蝦
So food is a way of appearance
所以食物是一種形態的方式出現
We made such a rule of thumb
我們就做了這樣的一個規納法
Then found a diet mentality
然後發現有個飲食心態
What about Kina?
規納來講的話呢
Eating adequate amounts of plant-based foods
比較吃適量足夠的植物性的食物
Contains fruits and vegetables
包含了蔬菜水果
lotus seed oil
荷果種子 油類
such food and drink
這樣的食物跟飲品
ok so tea is a drink
好 所以茶是一種飲品
That will provide phytochemicals
那都是會提供植化素的
so apart from what we know
所以除了我們知道的
fiber nutrients minerals
纖維 營養素 礦物之外
There is also a so-called phytochemical
還有一種所謂的植化素
You can see these proteins
這些蛋白質你一看就知道
is less saturated fat
是飽和脂肪比較少的
We all know that saturated fat causes inflammation
大家都知道飽和脂肪是會致發炎
when the body is aging
就是老化的時候身體
I just talked about the body having a low-grade inflammation
我剛剛講到身體有一種低度發炎狀態
then this will affect
那這個都會影響到
Your body's protein synthesis
你的身體的蛋白質的合成
According to the information just now
按照剛剛那些資訊
We organize it like this
我們把它整理在這樣子
just take a look
來看一下就是
For the prevention and treatment of senile dementia
對於防治老齡酩肉症的
Tips for this diet
這個飲食的提示
Moet's disease is a variety of nutrients
酩肉症都是有多種營養素
The condition of low intake
攝取偏低的狀況
but other than protein
但是除了蛋白質以外的
other these
其他這些
we really don't know
我們真的不知道
who is a key factor
誰是一個關鍵因素
interventional research
方法就是做介入研究
You observed that first let
你觀察到是先讓
Such a thing is given to the weak
這樣的一個東西就給予摔弱的人
Let's see if he eats well
看看他吃了會不會好
Anyway, the only thing that can be proven
反正是唯一能夠證實的
so what
那所以呢
From the information on the diet form just now,
我們從剛剛這個飲食形態的資料
we just wanted to say
我們就是在想說
if we follow
如果我們就按照
This from the US-Japan Dietary Guidelines
美日飲食指南的這個
This way of taking a balanced diet is recommended for the elderly
攝取均衡的這個方式來建議給老人
What if he does this?
他如果做到這樣子的話呢
He will first ensure that the nutrients are up to standard
他就先確保營養素達標
Contains protein will hit the mark
包含蛋白質會達標
Of course the low calorie one
那當然那個低熱量的
We're going to tweak the protein
我們要把它蛋白質調一下
Improved overall nutritional status
整體營養狀況改善
may be beneficial
可能就有利於
whole body system
整體的生理系統的
Maintenance of function and muscle mass
機能跟肌肉量的維持
That's the premise of a hypothesis we made
那就是我們做的一個假說的前提
that is
就是說
There is an important element that is
有個重要的要件就是說
More than 1500 calories
1500大卡以上
Protein is really okay
蛋白質確實沒有問題
But what if it's under 1500 calories?
但是如果是1500大卡以下的話呢
still need to make some adjustments
還要做一些調整
This paper only mentions that
這張紙只是提到就是說
If you are someone with different calories
如果你是有不同熱量的人
Oh 1300, 1400, 1600 to
喔1300、1400、1600到
The amount of meals everyone eats is slightly different
每個人每天吃的飯的量是略有不同
The protein will go up slowly
蛋白質就要慢慢慢慢上去了
vegetable
蔬菜
fruit
水果
besides
還有
our word in taiwan
我們在台灣的話
what we suggest
我們建議的如何
The category is stable and has not increased
品類是穩定的沒有增加
But on protein and protein
但是在蛋白質跟蛋白質上去的
There is a scaling like this
都有一個scaling這樣子上去
Then like this grease also goes up
然後像這個油脂也是有上去
So this data is hard to remember
所以這個數據很難記
enter your own data in
把自己的數據輸進去
then find your combination
然後找到你的組合
you just write it down
你就把它記下來
keep for reference
留著隨時參考
want to look like this
還要這個樣子
in the literature
在文獻上
If we look at the international literature
我們如果去看國際文獻
Found this with Shi Zhixixi
發現這個跟施志希希
There are quite a lot of related nutrients
相關的營養數也是蠻多的
Contains vitamin B complex
包含了維生素B群
Vitamin C Vitamin E Vitamin D
維生素C 維生素E 維生素D
There are also various plant chemicals
還有各種植化素
The most notable research it shows is that
最顯著的研究它顯現的就是
It is more certain that it is the intervention of vitamin B group
比較確定就是維生素B群的介入
Vitamin B complex has several B
維生素B群有好幾個B
Contains folic acid Grain number B2 Grain number B6
像包含葉酸 紋數B2 紋數B6
All of these follow
這幾個全部都跟
the synthesis of our neurotransmitters
我們的神經傳導物質的合成有關
They use MRI to measure the volume of the brain
它們是用MRI去測腦部的體積
It was found that head and group B
結果發現頭與B群
Can significantly slow down shrinkage
可以顯著的減緩萎縮
is now international
現在是國際上
The only study with good results
唯一的一個研究有很好的效果
But we believe this Shi Zhixihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihihi
但是我們相信這個施志希希希希希希希希希希希希希希希希
Quality also sees group B when cutting in with nutrients
質素還用營養素的切入的話是看到B群
What about the Nutritional Health Survey?
在營養健康調查呢
It is also found that it is related to this system
也發現就是跟這個施制
It's the people with low MMSE scores
就是MMSE的分數很低的這些人呢
it's basically a lot of stuff
它就基本上就是很多東西相關
very low heat
就熱量特別的偏低
protein fat with carbohydrates
蛋白質脂肪連碳水化物
B1 B2 B3 is nice
B1 B2 B3就是nice
B6 B12 CDE
B6 B12 CDE
False Calcium Maxim Zero Iron
假鈣美心 零鐵
Fatty Acid Regardless of Saturated Units
脂肪酸不論飽和單元對人
low in cholesterol and low in fiber
膽固醇都偏低 纖維偏低
So here is a phenomenon that appears when people get old
所以這邊顯現一個現象就是人到老的時候
Didn't you usually have heart disease and high cholesterol in the past?
一般過去不是都心臟病 膽固醇很高嗎
but by then
可是到那個時候
You have heart disease, high cholesterol
你就是心臟病 膽固醇高
At that time, it was not high anymore. They all came down.
那個時候也不高了 都下來了
So this time is to eat more
所以這個時候就是要多吃一個重點
After seeing such a result
看到這樣的一個結果之後
I think the diet of the last group of the elderly can be integrated
我就覺得老年最後群的飲食是可以整合的
Because the difference between weakening and restraining is not too big
因為衰弱跟施制差別不是太大
It is these proteins that must be taken care of
就是這一些蛋白質類都要給它顧全到
it's probably almost
就可能差不多了
low calorie intake
熱量都攝取偏低
Many macro and trace elements have lower levels of pearls to contain those
很多巨量微量元素都有顯珠較低的情況來包含那一些
something that shouldn't be high
就不該高的東西
like cholesterol and saturates
像膽固醇跟飽和子方
We both said we must
本來我們都說一定要
something low
低要低的東西
Now instead of saying
現在反倒就是說
your cholesterol but don't limit it
你膽固醇但也不要限制了
Don't limit the meat
肉也不要限制了
Because now it's just a matter of eating too little
因為現在就是吃太少的一個問題
Well, cognitive function is good
那麼認知功能好的
what about the elderly
這些高齡者呢
we just saw
我們剛剛看到就是
fresh fruits
新鮮水果
Whago Whole Milk
和果全股奶類
protein rich food
蛋白質豐富的食物
Like a man is fish Han seafood
像男性是魚漢海產
Women are eggs or soy products
女性是蛋或黃豆類製品
and tea and coffee
還有就是喝茶跟咖啡
a form of sauce
醬構成的一個形態
So our Taiwan
所以我們台灣的這個
with the international
跟國際上的
is very consistent
是非常一致的
In the long run, it starts from middle age
長期來講就是從中年開始
Of course you want to prevent
你當然就是要預防
cardiovascular disease
心臟血管疾病
This kind of thing like three high
這種三高這樣的一個東西
let this risk down
讓這個風險下降
short term
短期的話
You need to get enough nutrients
你要讓營養素充足
group b is enough
逼群要夠了
enough protein
蛋白質要夠了
tea or enough
喝茶啦或者要夠
Inside the National Construction Agency's plan
國建署的計畫裡面
we suggest
我們就建議說
The key to housing for geriatric syndrome
老年症候群房置的關鍵
Diet content
飲食內容
that is to say the first point
就是說第一點
You must balance the six categories
你一定要均衡地設入六大類
for those who eat less
對於食量少的人
The allocation of these six categories should be adjusted
要把這六大類分配做一個調整
we must emphasize
我們必須強調
what i just said
我剛剛講的這些
Vegetables, Nuts, Seed Circles, Dairy
蔬果 堅果 種子圈 各位奶類
and protein-rich foods
以及蛋白質豐富的食物
with healthy tea
要搭配健康茶飲
In terms of protein, what is better for the elderly?
蛋白質的話是什麼對老人比較好呢
Fish and seafood, including excuses
魚跟海鮮 包含藉口類啊這些
Egg Bean Meat
蛋 豆 肉
As for meat, less red meat
肉的話呢 紅肉要少
but it means to say
但是它的意思是說
People who eat less red meat
紅肉吃的少的人
Other people who eat a lot of meat are good
其他的這些肉吃的多的人不錯
But let's analyze it carefully
可是我們仔細進去分析
People with fewer lions and less sour meat
獅子也少 酸肉也少的人
did he eat red meat
他有沒有吃紅肉呢
he still has
他還是有的
don't say exclude it all
不要說是全部把它排除
don't do anything
千萬不要做任何事情
don't go too far
不要做太極端
we're talking about a trend
我們講的是一個趨勢
intervention target
介入目標
We are doing the same in the community now
我們現在在社區也這樣做就是
The first time we met an old man
第一個我們碰到一個老人的時候
We want to shun his personal heat
我們要顧順他的個人的熱量
Then we understand his six categories of allocation
然後我們就了解他的六大類分配
we are going to tell him
我們就要告訴他
and then assign it
然後把它的分配呢
how to adjust his main meal
怎麼樣調整他的主餐的
Distribution of the four food groups
四大類食物的分配
what is it like
就是什麼樣的
What kind of staple food
主食類 什麼樣的
Main course
主菜類
what kind of vegetables
怎麼樣的蔬菜
what kind of fruit to match
搭配什麼樣的水果
What about the allocation?
那這個分配呢
we would recommend using some
我們就會建議要用一些
three-dimensional space
三度空間的這種
plate you can easily understand
餐盤你可以很容易的了解
Then we ordinary people
那我們一般人的話
you can buy one
你可以一家可以買一個
After I got to know it, it took me a while to do yours.
了解之後呢就用了一段時間做你的
That amount is rooted in your mind
那個量就在你的腦子裡升根了
Where do you go out in the future, let alone take it with you
你以後出去哪裡更不用帶著
And that means creatively
另外就是說要以創意的方式
There are some things you may not normally be used to
有一些東西你可能平常沒有那個習慣
You need to have some imagination and creativity
你要自家有一些想像力跟創意
mix it in
把它搭配進去
Many of our friends are playing this activity all day long
這個活動我們許多的朋友一天到晚在玩
how to play this match how to match
玩這個怎麼配怎麼配
Then post it on Facebook.
然後就在臉書裡面公佈啊
Then pass it back and forth in LINE
然後LINE裡面傳來傳去
Very interesting
很有意思的
This can be turned into an event
這個可以變成一個活動
For example, a situation in our family is
譬如說我們家的一個狀況就是
my mother
我母親
My mother is a hundred years old now
我母親現在一百歲了
she is also very healthy
她身體也非常好
But she does eat less
但是她確實會有吃得比較少的情況
If there are vegetables left over from lunch or dinner
如果午餐或晚餐有蔬菜沒有吃完
then we'll collect it
那我們就會把它收集
For example, the next morning
譬如說隔天早上的時候
i'll chop it up
我就會把它剁碎
then with an egg
然後搭配一個蛋
turn into vegetable eggs
就變成蔬菜蛋
then put it on the sandwich
然後就放在它的三明治
For example like this
譬如說這樣子
then you just make sure it's veggies
那你就是確保它一定蔬菜
will eat
會有吃下去
This is an example
這是舉例啦
If it's fruit, it's me
水果的話呢就是我
My mother only has one appetite a day
我母親一天只有一個食慾
fruit that can only be eaten once
只能吃一次的水果
She can't eat in the afternoon and evening
她到下午跟晚上就吃不下
so i must help her with breakfast
所以我早餐一定幫她
prepare a bowl of fruit
備一碗水果
arrive
到了
if i go home at noon
如果中午我回家的話
I'll pour her a glass
我就會幫她倒一杯
100 percent orange juice
百分之百柳橙汁
put on the table
放在桌上
She will see it at noon
她中午起來就會看到
i'm busy
我很忙著
if i forget
如果我忘記
i go home at night
我晚上回家
Arrive home at half past five
五點半一到家
I'll start with a glass of 100 percent orange juice
我先倒一杯百分之百柳橙汁
or grape juice
或是葡萄汁
put it over there
放在那邊
just ask her to drink first
就請她先喝
then wait until i make dinner
然後再等我做晚餐